Hello, and welcome to Lesson 23 of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
大家好 欢迎来到本次与沃尔夫兰大学合作的微积分入门第23课
The topic for this lesson is Riemann sums.
本节课的课题是黎曼和
Let’s begin with a brief overview of the lesson.
我们先来简单介绍一下本课的内容
Basically there are two fundamental aspects of calculus.
基本上微积分有两个基本方面
The first aspect is differential calculus,
第一个方面是微分计算
and that’s what we’ve been talking about all the time so far.
这也是到目前为止我们一直在谈论的
Now the prime motivation over there is to find the slope of a curve at a point of the tangent line.
现在那边的首要动机是求出曲线在切线某点的斜率
Now the second aspect of calculus is the so-called integral calculus,
现在微积分的第二个方面就是所谓的积分微积分
and that is what we’ll cover from now on.
这也是我们从现在开始要做的事情
Now the basic motivation, the prime motivation for this part of calculus is quite simple.
现在基本的动机 这部分微积分的首要动机很简单
Basically here is a plot of this function, and the problem is that
基本上这里是这个函数的图 问题是
you’d like to find this area under the curve for the function.
你想找到这个函数的曲线下面积
In this lesson, what we’ll do is we’ll devise a precise way
在本课中我们要做的是 我们将设计一个精确的方式
of expressing this notion of area under the curve mathematically.
曲线下的面积这一概念在数学上的表达
Okay. Let’s begin with some review of your earlier work.
好吧 我们先来回顾一下您之前的工作
If you have a rectangle, then its area is length times width.
如果你有一个矩形 那么它的面积就是长度乘以宽度
On the other hand, if it were a triangle, then its area is base times height over 2.
另一方面 如果它是一个三角形 那么它的面积就是底乘以高度除以 2
But if you have a general polygon, what you’d do is you’d break it up into triangles,
但如果你有一个一般的多边形 你要做的是把它分解成三角形
then find the area of each one triangle and then add them all together.
然后找出每一个三角形的面积 再把它们加在一起
Now the area of a circle is a bit harder because it involves the number π,
现在圆的面积有点难 因为它涉及到数字 π
but that’s straightforward to work with.
但这是直接的工作
The question now is what happens if you have a more general curve?
现在的问题是 如果你有一条更随机的曲线会怎样
Let’s say you have this parabola, and you want to find the area under the parabola.
假设你有一条抛物线 你想找到抛物线下的面积
How do you work it out?
你怎么解决
To motivate our discussion, let’s recall the idea of the slope at a point.
为了激发我们的讨论 让我们回顾一下某点的斜率的概念
Let’s say if you have a differentiable function, then the slopes of
比方说 如果你有一个可微分函数 那么斜率为
the secant lines at a point will eventually approach some value m,
在某一点上的割线最终会接近某个值 m
which is the slope of the tangent at that point.
即该点的切线的斜率
Here’s an example to illustrate that.
这里有一个例子
You have a curve x^2 and you have a point (1, 1) on it,
你有一条曲线 x^2 上面有一个点 （1，1）
and you want to work out the slope at that point.
而你要在这一点上计算出坡度
At the moment, the slope is 3.618 for the secant,
目前 秒速时时彩开奖走势图的斜率为 3.618
but what I’ll do now is I’ll try and bring the point Q closer to P,
但我现在要做的是 我将试着使 Q 点接近 P
and as I bring it closer, the value of the slope
当我把它拉近 斜率的值
approaches the correct value, which is eventually 2.
接近正确值 最终是 2
That’s the idea of slope at a point.
这就是一点上的斜率的概念
You take secant lines, and then you take the limit of those lines
你把割线 然后你把这些线的极限
as you approach the point.
接近该点时
A similar idea can be used for areas; namely, break up the areas
对于区域也可以采用类似的思路 即把区域分开
into separate rectangles, and then you add up all those rectangle areas
成单独的矩形 然后将所有这些矩形面积相加
and then you get an approximate area for the region.
然后你就可以得到该区域的大致面积
For example, if you take the same curve and you break it up
例如 如果你把同一条曲线拆开 你就会发现
into four rectangles over here, then you see that the area approximately,
在这里拆分成成四个长方形 然后你看大概的面积
but of course a wide space tells you that
但当然 广阔的空间告诉你
there is some error in the approximation.
近似值有一定的误差
Now if you take more rectangles—let’s say you take 10 rectangles—
现在如果你取更多的矩形 比方说你取10个矩形
you will get a better approximation, and then as you increase
你会得到一个更好的近似值 然后随着你增加
the number of rectangles, you will get a better and better approximation, hopefully.
矩形的数量 你会得到一个更更好的近似值
That’s the idea of area which we want to explore.
这就是我们想要探索的区域理念
Let’s begin now with a parabola again and try and work with rectangles
现在我们再从抛物线开始 试着用长方形来进行处理
which have the top-left corner at the point on the curve.
其中左上角为曲线上的点
What you see here is that in this case, you actually have
你在这里看到的是 在这种情况下 你实际上有
an underestimation of the total area, so the answer which you get is less than the total area.
低估的总面积 所以你得到的答案是小于总面积的。
For example,  in this case your corners are at 0, 0.2, et cetera,
例如 在这种情况下 你的角在 0 0.2 等等
and you can work out the area.
你就可以计算出面积
Then you get back the answer, 0.21875.
然后你会得到答案 0.21875
Those over here are just the function values.
这边的只是函数值
Okay. On the other hand, if you took the top-right corner for each rectangle,
另一方面 如果你看每个矩形的右上角
then you can see you’re going to overestimate the area under the curve,
那么你可以看到你会高估曲线下的面积
so in this case you get back the answer, 0.46875.
所以在这种情况下 你得到的答案 0.46875
It looks like the answer would lie somewhere between 0.21875 and 0.46875.
看来答案应该在 0.21875 和 0.46875 之间
That’s the conclusion from the earlier slide which I am repeating over here again.
这就是前面幻灯片的结论 我在这里再重复一遍
What happens as you increase the number of rectangles?
当你增加矩形的数量时会发生什么？
Well, you see over here that as you have a larger and larger number
嗯 你看这里 当你有一个越来越大的数量
of rectangles, then the lower and the upper estimates become closer and closer,
的矩形 那么下限和上限的估计就会越来越接近
and they are almost identical eventually.
而且它们最终几乎完全相同
The plots over here show you what’s happening over here.
这边的剧情让你看到这边的情况
As you have a larger number of rectangles,
由于你的矩形数量较多
you get a better and better approximation to the area,
你会得到一个更好的近似的区域
and finally it looks like you actually get the area.
最后看来你真的得到了这个区域
But that only happens when you take a limit.
但这只有在你施加约束时才会发生
The area will approach 1/3, but that will only actually happen if you take a limit.
面积会接近 1/3 但这只有在你施加约束时才会真正发生
Here’s a required limit. 1/n is the width of each rectangle,
这里有一个必要的约束 1/n 是每个矩形的宽度
and that’s the functional value, the height.
而这就是功能函数 高度。
The limit over here is 1/3—that’s the upper limit—and the lower limit
这里的限制是 1/3 这是上限
would be to take the other end of the rectangle,
也是下限将是取长方形的另一端
and then you get back 1/3 as the answer in this case as well.
然后在这种情况下 你也会得到 1/3 的答案
Okay. Now to get a bit more general, I need to talk about so-called Riemann sums.
好吧 现在说得更笼统一点 我需要谈谈所谓的黎曼和。
Now this is a fairly difficult concept, so let me go slowly.
现在这个概念相当难 让我慢慢说
Let’s say you have a general function f[x], not just a parabola,
比方说 你有一个普通的函数 f[x] 而不仅仅是一条抛物线
and you want to work out the area under the curve between [a, b].
你要计算 [a, b] 之间的曲线下面积
What you do is you first break it up into n rectangles
您要做的是首先将其分解成 n 个矩形
so each rectangle will have a width (b – a)/n.
所以每个矩形的宽度为 (b-a)/n
This quantity is called Δx. Δ means very small.
这个量叫做 Δx Δ的意思是非常小
Now you’ve broken up your interval [a, b] into n smaller intervals,
现在您已经将您的区间 [a，b] 分解成 n 个较小的区间
[x0, x1], [x1, x2], et cetera, and the left endpoint is a, the right endpoint is b.
[x0，x1]，[x1，x2] 等等 左端点为 a 右端点为b
For each subinterval, you have the endpoints given by just adding Δx every time.
对于每个子间隔 你只要每次加上 Δx 就可以得到端点
What you see over here is the area of any one rectangle
你在这里看到的是任何一个矩形的面积
will be the width of the rectangle times the height.
将是矩形的宽度乘以高度
Let’s say if you work with the right-aligned rectangles,
比方说 如果你用右对齐的矩形
then that height will be f[xi].
那么该高度将是 f[xi]
That’s the total area, the sum, but if you work out the left-aligned rectangles,
这就是总面积 总和 但如果你把左对齐的矩形计算出来
then you get a similar sum, but with xi – 1 as the point which you evaluate.
那么你就会得到一个类似的和 但是用 xi - 1 作为你评估的点
These sums are called Riemann sums because
这些和被称为黎曼和 因为
they were discovered by the famous German mathematician Bernhard Riemann.
它们是由德国著名数学家 伯恩哈德·黎曼 发现的
Here’s an example that shows what’s happening.
这里有一个例子可以说明发生了什么
You have the curve Sin[x] + 2, and you want to see what happens
你有一条曲线 Sin[x]+2 你想看看会发生什么事？
as you increase the number of rectangles.
当你增加矩形的数量时
Let’s play the animation.
我们来播放动画
You see that you get a better limit approximation
你看 你会得到一个更好的极限近似
as you increase the number of rectangles.
当你增加矩形的数量时
But of course, things are not so simple because at some places,
但当然 事情并不那么简单 因为在一些地方
you get a slightly smaller area, and at some others,
你得到的面积稍小 而在其他一些
you overestimate the area.
你高估了面积
Okay. Now we can make a formal definition of area.
好了 现在我们可以给面积下个正式定义了
The area under the curve is defined by
曲线下的面积定义为
the limit of the sum of the areas of the rectangles.
矩形面积之和的极限
Now that’s the case for right-aligned because you’re working with f[xi],
现在是右对齐的情况 因为你是在用 f[xi]
but if you want left-aligned rectangles, then you get almost the same expression,
但如果你想要左对齐的矩形 那么你得到的表达式几乎是一样的
but now you start at 0 rather than starting at 1.
但现在你从 0 开始 而不是从 1 开始
The fact is that if your function f is continuous,
事实上 如果你的函数 f 是连续的
then both those limits will exist, and in fact, they’ll be equal.
那么这两个极限都将存在 事实上 它们将是平等的
You could work with those sums, or you could actually take the values
你可以用这些总和来计算 或者你可以实际取值
at any number in the subinterval for each i.
在每个 i 的子间隔中的任何数字
These numbers are called sample points.
这些数字被称为样本点
In particular, if you have right-aligned rectangles,
特别是 如果你有右对齐的矩形
then you have the sample points xi, and if you have left-aligned rectangles,
然后你有样本点 xi 如果你有左对齐的矩形
then you have the sample points xi – 1.
那么你有样本点 xi - 1
That’s the general formula for the area
这就是面积的一般公式
with any sample points for each subinterval.
与每个子间隔的任何样本点
For example, here you have taken the sample points
例如 在这里 你已经采取了样本点
to be the midpoints of each subinterval.
为每个子区间的中点
Okay. Now it’s time to work out an example,
好了 现在是时候举个例子了
so let’s try to work out the area of Sin[x] from 0 to b
所以让我们试着计算出 Sin[x] 从 0 到 b 的面积
where the number b lies between 0 and π.
其中数字 b 位于 0 和 π 之间
Here’s a plot. Now we break up the interval into n subintervals.
这是一个图 现在我们将区间分解成 n 个子区间
We’ll work with, let’s say, right-aligned rectangles,
我们将使用 比方说 右对齐的矩形
and you get the answer for the area as 1 – Cos[b].
你可以得到面积的答案为 1 - Cos[b]
Of course, you could then replace the b with π,
当然你可以把 b 换成π
and you get back a much nicer answer, which is just 2.
而你得到的答案要好得多 这只是 2
That’s the power of the whole method; namely, it gives the exact answer
这就是整个方法的威力 即它给出了准确的答案
under this curve between, in this case, 0 and π.
在这条曲线下 在这种情况下 0 和 π 之间
Okay. Now a slightly more practical problem.
好了 现在说一个稍微实际一点的问题
Let’s say a car moves on a highway, and you’re given the velocities
假设一辆汽车在高速公路上行驶 每隔10分钟 你会得到的速度
at different times at 10-minute intervals, and you want to work out
你想得到
the total distance covered in 100 minutes.
100分钟内的总路程。
What you do is you divide by 60 over here—
你要做的是用 60 除以这里
after all, you want to work with minutes—and you take the height,
毕竟 你要用分钟来工作 而你得到高度。
so to speak, as the velocities, so you take 63, 62, 61, et cetera, from here,
可以说 作为速度 所以你把63 62 61 等等 从这里
and you get back the sum, which is just the distance covered.
而你拿回来的总和 只是覆盖的距离
You can also take the heights to be the velocities at the right endpoints
你也可以把高度当作右端点的速度
like I’ve done over here, in which case you get back the answer 108.33.
就像我在这里做的那样 在这种情况下 你得到的答案是 108. 33
That’s a plot of the velocities, and we’ve worked out distance in two ways
这是速度的曲线图 我们用两种方法计算出了距离
using the left values and the right values.
使用左值和右值
But of course we could be more precise and assume that the velocity
但当然我们可以更精确地假设
is given by a certain function, in which case you could work out
速度是由某个函数给出的 在这种情况下 你可以计算出
the distance by a similar method as earlier on.
用类似前面的方法来计算距离
You take the limit of the sum, and then velocities must be then
你取和的极限 那么速度一定
found out at those values over here.
在这里的这些值
Then you get back the answer as 109.394 in this case.
那么在这种情况下 你得到的答案是 109.394
That’s a plot of velocity, and the area under the curve in this case
那是速度的曲线图 在这种情况下 曲线下的面积
will give you the distance covered in that interval of time.
将给你在该时间段内所覆盖的距离
That brings me to the end of this lesson.
本课至此就结束了
Basically, finding area is a very practical matter.
基本上 寻找面积是一件非常实际的事情
You’ve done it forever, so to speak,
可以说 你已经做了一辈子了
from, let’s say, middle school all the way up.
、比方说，初中一直到现在
But to work out the area under a general curve,
但为了求出一般曲线下的面积
you must divide into rectangles and then add those areas up.
你必须分成长方形 然后把这些区域加起来
Finally, we are doing calculus, so you must take the limit
最后 我们在做微积分 所以你一定要把极限
as those rectangle numbers approach infinity,
当这些矩形数字接近无穷大时
and then you get the real area under the curve.
然后你就可以得到曲线下的实际面积
Now, these sums that you compute are called Riemann sums
现在 你计算的这些和叫做黎曼和
in honor of the mathematician Riemann,
为了纪念数学家黎曼
and these Riemann sums can also be used to work out
而这些黎曼和也可以用来计算出
the total distance traveled when you are given only the velocity.
当你只给你速度时 总的移动距离
That’s the end of this lesson.
这节课就到此为止
The next lesson will talk about Riemann sums in more detail,
下节课将详细讲黎曼和
but before doing that, there will be a problem session,
但在做之前 会有一个问题环节
which you should certainly look at and understand the topic in much greater detail.
你一定要看清楚 更详细地了解这个话题
Thank you very much. I’ll stop over here.
谢谢你了今天就到这里吧
翻译 彭彦鸿